呼呀！
Hoo-ya!
噢！
Oh!
带劲！
Munched!
为这星球上最庞大的机器巨兽欢呼吧！
Give it up for the baddest beast machines on the planet!
行行好把音量调低点行吗？
Would you mind lowering the volume?
嘿 救护车
Hey, Ratch
来看看上个星期神子带我去看的怪兽卡车拉力赛
check out the monster truck rally Miko took me to last week.
我在手机上存了些精彩片段
I compiled some highlights with my cell phone.
无辜的车辆为了取悦人类观众而互相厮杀？
Innocent vehicles battling for the pleasure of human spectators?
太暴力了！
Blood sport!
- 没错！
- Yea!
你应该去野外给擎天柱搭把手
You could be helping Optimus in the field right now.
啊 他用不着我去找什么古代教育的…
Ah, he doesn't need my help to search for some ancient educational…
…鬼东西
… thingamabob.
你嘴里的这个“鬼东西”正是塞博特恩的数据经筒
The "thingamabob" to which you refer happens to be a Cybertronian data cylinder.
嘿！
Hey!
这其中浩瀚的智慧根本无法言喻
And there is no telling what vast intelligence it may hold.
在黄金时代
During the Golden Age
许多这样的经筒被制造出来
dozens of these cylinders were created
每一个都储藏着塞博特恩的所有知识 涵盖一切科目
each containing the sum total of Cybertronian knowledge on any given subject:
恒星成像学 医学 古神话…
stellar cartography, medicine, ancient mythology.
后来战争爆发
When the war broke out
这些经筒被隐匿到各个星系
the cylinders were hidden throughout the galaxies
以防被霸天虎染指
to keep them as far as possible from Decepticon reach.
能在这里探测到一个经筒
Detecting one signal here
在地球上 就有可能…
on Earth, is the opportunity of a...
呃… 你话太多了 哥们
Eh... T.M.I., dude.
把频道调回去 我想看完这整场节目
Switch it back, I want to see the hoedown showdown.
救护车 有霸天虎的埋伏！
Ratchet, Decepticon ambush!
经筒有危险
The cylinder is at risk!
我们需要支援
We require backup!
我天生就是提供支援的
Backup is what I'm built for.
砸了他们的挡泥板 小隔
Go bend some fenders, Bulk.
我也有个重要的任务要交给你 神子
I have an important mission for you, too. Miko.
真的？
Really?
啊…
Agh...
汽车人 坚守阵地
Autobots, stand your ground.
这件文物绝对不能落入敌手！
the artifact must not fall into enemy hands!
到爸爸这来
Come to papa.
回你妈那去
Run to mommy!
叫叔叔 快叫！
Say uncle. Say it!
救护车 回话！
Ratchet, come in!
神子？这可是紧急频道
Miko? This is an emergency channel.
我们得保持它畅通 以防… 等等…
We need to keep it open for the Auto... Wait...
你在哪里？
Where are you?
我就在那鬼东西旁边
D'oy! I'm with the thingamabob!
鬼东…数据经筒！
Thingama... the data cylinder!
没错 你能把这东西从这带走吗？
Yes, can you bridge it out of here?
我会重新启动你那里的坐标
I'll reactivate arrival coordinates.
老兄 你能把它开得再近一点吗？
Dude, can you open it any closer?
给我提供坐标
Supply coordinates.
呃… 五十码？
Ugh... Fifty yards?
精确的坐标！
Precise coordinates!
一 二 哈啊啊啊…
One, two, Hahhhhh...
哇噢…
Whoa...
神子？
Miko?
不！
No!
小隔！
Bulk!
你真是员得力干将 隔板
You really took one for the team, Bulkhead
不过是我们这边的
my team.
隔板 你没事吧？
Bulkhead, are you…
没事 像挠了一下痒痒
Fine. I didn't even smart.
我帮了倒忙把那东西弄丢了
I helped loose that thing.
我想帮忙去找
I want to help find it.
我要去现场协助擎天柱
I need to get back in the field with Optimus.
你现在要接受我的监护 这是擎天柱的命令
You are under my watch now -- Optimus' orders.
花点时间给你做个神经网络大检查才是明智之举
And running a full scan of your neural network would be a wiser use of your time.
拜托 医生
Come on, doc.
没什么好检查的
There's nothing up there to scan.
我感觉他挺好
He seems fine to me.
好吧 如果你一定要干点什么
Well, if you insist on making yourself useful.
你可以帮神子一起打扫
You can help Miko tidy up.
呃！
Ughhh!
简直是鸡毛当令箭！
He's mad with power!
呵呵呵 救护车就是那样的
Hehehe, that's Ratchet.
零向量平方 是吧？
Null vector squared, alright?
什么？
What?
嘿 我们有油漆吗？
Hey, we got any paint around here?
你要搞艺术？酷！
Art project? Cool!
你说“它是空的”是什么意思？
What do you mean "it's empty"?
威震天陛下
Lord Megatron
这些经筒就像电池一样
these cylinders are not unlike batteries.
数据以某种能量形式存储在里面
The data is stored within them as a form of energy.
刚扫描到的时候它还是满的
It's scanned fully charged.
所以我们才能对它定位
That's how we located it to begin with.
但是现在…
But now...
废电池一只
Dead battery.
是你摔的吗 独眼白痴？
Did you drop it, you one-eye oaf?
不是的 主人
No, master.
我还没来得及碰 它就给隔板来了一下子
I wasn't gonna touch the thing after it put a zap on Bulkhead.
嘿 你想会不会…
Hey, you think...
我懂了
I know.
我必须弄清楚这个罐子到底装过什么东西
And I must find out what that vessel contained.
在那些古人的秘密中
When it comes to the secrets of the ancients
知识也是力量
knowledge can be power.
我是认真的 救护车
Seriously, Ratch
你得来看看隔板画的东西
you need to see what Bulk's painting in here.
好吧 要是不见识一下隔板的钢铁人生
Yes, I'm sure "one hasn't truly lived until one‘s beheld
就算是白活了
Bulkhead's take on steel life with lugnuts".
看 我跟你说什么来着？
See, did I tell you or what?
三分之一的r立方求导得到r dr r
The differential of one third r cubed is r-dr-r
那不是艺术
That is not art.
是科学
It's science.
你看到的这个红点
This hot spot you see here.
这是信息 数据 活生生的能量
It's information, data, living energy.
等一下 你说这是活的 还很旺盛
Hold on. It's alive, it's on fire
而且还在隔板脑子里？
and it's in Bulkhead's brain?
冷静点 神子
Chill, Miko.
数据仅仅是寄宿在我大脑的一部分空间内
The data is only inhabiting a fraction of my brain.
相比神经网络的密度规模就是无穷小
Infinitesimal by standard neural net densities.
等等… 我怎么懂这些东西？
Wait... how do I know all that?
从战斗时发生的事看来
Based on what we witness during our skirmish
这种活生生的数据肯定设定了程序
the living data must have been programmed to eject
当感知到异常接触的时候就发射出去
when it sensed unauthorized access.
安全措施
A security measure.
它本来要向空中发射
It would have jettisoned heavenward.
消失在星际之间
Lost to the stars.
没想到我的胖引擎挡住了路
Except my fat engine block got in the way.
每个在场的虎子都拿过它
Every Con there made a grab for it.
但经筒只在神子碰了之后才启动的？
But the cylinder doesn't go off until Miko touches it?
经筒起源于塞博特恩的黄金时代
The cylinders originated from Cybertron's Golden Age
那时还没有汽车人和霸天虎之分
pre-dating the Autobot-Decepticon division.
所以它不会把任何塞博特恩人当成威胁
So it wouldn't consider any native of Cybertron to be a threat.
只有外星生命体 比如人类
Only alien life forms, such as humans.
那这些是高深理论 还是胡话？
Are we staring at genius, or gibberish?
尽管可能是空欢喜一场
I do not wish to falsely rally anyone's hopes
但这些工式似乎是人造能量的方程式
but these equations appear to be the formula for a synthetic Energon.
我们挖到宝了？
We hit the mother lode?
神子 你明白这意味着什么吗？
Miko, do you understand what this means?
呃…
Um...
能量给我们提供燃料
Energon provides our fuel
弹药 还有我们的生命力量
our ammo, our life force.
地球上天然的能量如此稀缺
With the natural stuff in such short supply here on Earth
这可以解决许许多多的问题
this could solve a whole lot of problems.
比如 提供为我们逆转战争形势的优势
Such as, providing us with the edge we need to turn the tide of this war.
或者 获得复兴塞博特恩的关键技术
Or, handing us the key to revitalizing Cybertron.
我们拿到了实物
We got the goods
而威震天所拿到的只有一个空罐子
and all Megatron got was an empty bucket.
我何曾有过用脑子还能大显身手的时候？
How often do I get to use my knocking to save the day?
原子坐标的交点显示出收敛的三级结构
Intersection of atomic coordinates indicate convergent tertiary structures.
- 你还没写完吗？\N- 简单转化数据是不可逆的
- Are you done yet?\N- Simply converting data is irreversible
最终产生不对称…
resulting in asymmetric...
不得不说
Got to admit
聪明模式的隔板感觉有点奇怪
it's weird seeing Bulk in brainiac mode.
向量L模值的平方
Vector L norm squared.
休息时间！
Break time!
来场风驰电掣的街头赛车7如何？
How about a lightening round of T.M.T. street racer 7?
能量温度与体积比例… 三分角技巧
Energon temperatures in volume proportional... angle trisector construction.
又该你记录了 救护车
Got another round for you to log, Ratchet.
上一次我们看到隔板的神经网络是这样的
This is Bulkhead's neural net as you saw it earlier.
这是几分钟前新的扫描记录
This scan was recorded just minutes ago.
我担心的就是这个――
It is as I feared --
这些数据正在积极地 侵蚀性地
-- the data seems to be actively and aggressively
重写隔板的神经网络
re-writing Bulkhead's neural net.
我曾指望他能清除数据
I had hoped he was purging the data
但他似乎只顾着照抄这些数据 而这些数据
but he seems to be merely transcribing it, as it...
正在占据他的思维
Consumes his mind.
所有迹象表明
From all indications
当隔板完成方程式时
by the time Bulkhead completes the formula
他自己的思想 他的记忆
his own thought, his memories
都会被抹掉
could be wiped clean.
但是如果我们阻止了他
But if we stop him
那就等于挥别了人造能量
good-bye synthetic Energon.
前提是我们能找到阻止他的方法
You assume we possess a means of stopping him.
我还不能立即理解古人的智慧
I don't exactly have instant access to the wisdom of the ancients.
我不能容忍又一个战友牺牲
I will not allow another one of our own to be sacrificed.
不惜一切代价
No matter the cost.
如果这些有生命的数据把自己从经筒里传输出来
If the living data transmitted itself from the cylinder
也许我们能 用些什么办法把它再塞回去
perhaps we could somehow coaks it back inside.
我们又怎么从霸天虎手中夺回经筒？
How are we supposed to get it back from the Decepticons?
威震天会主动送过来的
Megatron will bring it to us.
子集放大后的摩擦系数值…
Friction coefficient quotient of the subset amplified...
想要放大音量吗？
You want amplified?
证明观测者悖论在此处不适用…
Proving perceptor's paradox is nothing of a kind.
啊！怎么回事？
Nah! What is that?
金属 你喜欢这首歌
Metal. You loved this song.
我需要集中精力
I'm trying to concentrate.
呃… 你的口气越来越像救护车了！
Ughh... You are starting to sound just like Ratchet!
谁？
Who?
救护车 我觉得隔板有些失去理智了
Ratch, I think Bulk's losing his mind.
你… 已经知道了…
You... already know...
神子 我们不想吓到你
Miko, we didn't want to frighten you
不过你放心
but rest assured
擎天柱已经有计划了
Optimus has a plan.
擎天柱不是隔板的医生
Optimus isn't Bulkhead's doctor.
我只想知道
I just need to know
等隔板念完那些方程式
when Bulk's done spitting out that formula
他会重新变回原来那个隔板 对吗？
he'll go back to being regular old Bulkhead, right?
威震天陛下 我们探测到了一个熟悉的能量信号
Lord Megatron, we've detected a familiar energy profile.
数据的？
The data?
隔板离开了他们基地的保护屏障
Bulkhead must have left the shielded radius of their base.
打击和我要去…
Breakdown and I will...
再搞砸一次？
Fail me again?
擎天柱
Optimus.
显然你不是我想见到的汽车人
You're certainly not the Autobot I expected to find here.
不过 让我猜猜――
But let me guess --
你装备了发射器 伪造了我想找的数据信号
you rigged the transponder to mimic the frequency of the data I seek.
威震天 我有个提议
Megatron, I have a proposal.
但说无妨
I'm… listening.
交出经筒
Surrender the cylinder
我会把它重新充满 并还给你
and I will return it to you fully restored.
这个小玩意儿？
This trinket right here?
请你告诉我
And pray tell
它到底装了什么不祥之物 你如此急于脱手？
what trifles did it hold that you are so anxious to give away?
接受我的提议 你自然就知道了
Accept my terms, and you will find out.
你还记得千斤顶将他唯一的手雷\N扔进霸天虎热交换机的场景吗？
Do you remember the time you watched Wheeljack lobbed his only grenade into Decepticon heat-exchanger?
谁？
Who?
千斤顶！你最好的伙伴…
Wheeljack! Your best bud--
当然 除了我以外的
beside me, of course.
你还知道我是谁吗？
Do you even know who I am?
当然 你是…
Of course, you're...
等同于扁球体的F拓扑中心的n次方
Equivalent to the Fréchet mean of the oblate spheroid to the N power.
孤立的E的内能仍为常量
Internal energy of the isolated E remains constant.
继续干 隔板
Keep them coming, Bulkhead.
过来
Come on.
你想完成你的方程式 是不是？
You want to finish your formula, don't you?
你接受我的提案吗？
Do you accept my proposal?
威震天陛下…
Lord Megatron...
给我点时间
Give me a moment.
您找到想找的东西了吗？
Did you find what you were looking for?
情况复杂
It's complicated.
嗯 击倒和我好像找到了隔板
Well, Breakdown and I may have located the bogie
充满数据的
fully charged.
说下去
Proceed.
只有一个小问题…我们没有经筒
Just one hitch -- we don't have the cylinder.
那就把隔板的脑袋给我带回来
Then bring me the head of Bulkhead.
看 你喜欢怪兽卡车
Look, you love monster trucks.
记得我们上周在节目结束之后偷偷溜进这里吗？
Remember when we snuck in here after the show last week?
质量与散逸率平方乘积恒定
Mass times diffusion rate squared is constant.
所有这些就没有一样能让你想起点什么吗？
Is any of this ringing a bell?
钟形曲线？不不不
Bell curve? No, no, no
那不吻合
that wouldn't factor in.
我们星期天早上的沙丘冲刺呢？
How about our Sunday morning dune-bashings?
去看歪猴子的表演呢？
Rocking out to Slash Monkey?
帮我做作业呢？
Helping me with my homework?
陷阱问题！
Trick question!
你知道我不做作业…
You know I don't do homework...
对吗？
Don't you?
好吧 不管过去怎样
OK, forget the past.
从现在开始我们能制造新的回忆
Starting now, we can make new memories.
热能的三次根UΔE违反苦朗克能量守恒定律
The cube root of the exothermic energon U delta E violates Clank's Law of energon conservation.
隔板 我知道你内心的某个地方会一直记得我
Bulkhead, I know somewhere inside you always remember me
我只是想让你知道
and I just want you to know
我永远不会忘记你
I'll never forget you.
真感人！
Boo hoo!
我眼睛都要流润滑油了
I'm shedding lubricant.
现在立刻跟我走
Follow me right now
否则这些家伙会…
or these guys are gonna...
偷走方程式！
steal the formula!
我的方程式？
My equations?
快来 快来！
Come on, come on!
临阵脱逃并不像是隔板的作风
Not like Bulkhead to run from a fight.
恐怕我们的朋友是思考过度了
I'm afraid our friend has had a little too much to think.
威震天陛下 我们很顺利
Lord Megatron, we are good.
擎天柱 经过我仔细的考虑
Optimus, upon careful consideration
如果你想要经筒
if you want the cylinder
你必须自己来抢
you'll have to take it.
好吧 捉迷藏游戏
OK, then, fun and games.
出来吧 出来吧 不管你在哪里
Come out, come out, wherever you are.
呃…虎子们干扰了信号
Ugh... the Cons are scrambling the signal.
多边形的三分线是不可分子集
The trisector the polygon is an integral subset.
嘘… 安静！
Shhh... quiet!
不管你做什么 别动
And whatever you do, keep still.
我试着离远一点再请求支援
I'm gonna see if I can get far enough to call for backup.
隔板 是你吗？
Bulkhead, is that you?
打击 别管那个人类了
Breakdown, forget the human.
游戏的有趣之处
Games are only fun to play…
就是快赢的时候
… when you are winning.
我想我赢了
I think I'm warm.
EM3除以斥力系数的平方根等于…
EM3 devided by the square root of a propulsion factor equals...
你弄脏了我的喷漆！
You painted my paint job!
准备挨刀吧！
Prepare for surgery!
你的脑袋归我了
Heads, you lose.
不！
No!
好吧 既然如此 就谁也别想要
Well, in that case, no one gets it.
擎天柱 隔板和神子离开了基地
Optimus, Bulkhead and Miko have abandoned base.
我有他们的环陆桥坐标
I have their GroundBridge coordinates.
把我们传送回来 快
Bridge us back, immediately.
又来了？趴下！
Not again! Get down!
我又惊动它了？
I did it again?
隔板？
Bulkhead?
废电池一只
Dead battery.
如果我们丢了数据 威震天会刮了我的喷漆
Megatron will peel our paint for losing that data.
所以我们必须得扒了你的皮
So we are gonna have to peel you.
还是溜之大吉吧
Or, peel out of here.
隔板…
Bulkhead...
数据已经被完全清除了
The data has been fully expelled
但隔板却仍然完全没有反应
but Bulkhead remains completely unresponsive.
因为那能量将隔板的意识一起带走了
Because the energy took Bulkhead's mind with it.
飞向天际 消失在群星之间
Heavenward. Lost to the stars.
因为我的错 你们永远都不会知道方程式剩余的部分了
It's my fault you'll never know the rest of the formula
也是因为我 隔板永远地消失了
and it's my fault Bulkhead's gone forever.
神子 你的机智应对
Miko, your quick thinking prevented the formula
阻止了方程式落入霸天虎手中
from falling into Decepticon hands.
如果有谁会赞成这种行为的话 那一定是隔板
If anyone would've backed that plan, it's Bulkhead.
现在就对他的状况下结论还为时过早
It's simply too early to know the extend of his condition.
很简单的一些事 比如熟悉的景色
Something as simple as a familiar sight
气味 甚至只是声音
or smell, perhaps even a sound
都有可能唤醒隔板
could trigger Bulkhead's awakening.
隔板？
Bulkhead?
邦… 邦…
Gang... Bang...
我喜欢那首歌！
I love that song!
神子？
Miko?